Guide to the Rose Goldsen papers, [ca. 1950-1985]
Goldsen, Rose papers, [ca. 1950-1985]
- Series V. Author Files
  - H.F. Harlow, M.K. Harlow and S.J. Suomi, "From Thought to Therapy: Lessons From a Primate Laboratory" 1971 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    [with RKG notes]
  - Hilda T. Himmelweit, "The Open University's Impact," 8th International World of Tomorrow Meeting, Perugia, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Glen Hirsch and Alan Lewis, "Strategies for Access to Public Service Advertising" (San Francisco: Public Media Center, 1976) (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - John Howard and James Hulbert, "Advertising and the Public Interest" - staff report to the FTC, chs. 1-5 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Howard and Hulbert, ch. 6-end (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Humanity & Society 11/81 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - I-J (Box 19, Folder 21)
    [IDOC (International Documentation on the Contemporary Church); Alexander B. Jackson - diary c mugger 7/73; Julian Jaynes, Saugerties, 1979 - RKG notes; Brooks Johnson and Bob Jones, "Labor's Love 1 An American Trilogy - Arbitration in Labor and Management"; Gerald Jonas, "Into the Brain" 7/74]
  - Ivan Ilich (Box 19, Folder 22)
    ["Vernacular Values and Economics" 3/80; "To Pedal a Theory" 9/73 w/ RKG notes; John Ohliger and Colleen McCarthy, "Lifelong Learning or Lifelong Schooling? A Tentative View of the Ideas of Ivan Ilich (Syracuse University, 7/71)]
  - Institute Colombiano de Desarrollo Social (ICODES): Estructura y Funcionamiento de los Medios de Comunicacion Social en Colombia Fc. 1971-21 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Institut des Sciences Humaines Appliquees (Bordeaux] Problemes D'Enseignement en Haute-Volta - Monograph: Village Mossi n.d. (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Institute Torcuato di Telia (Buenos Aires): Memoria 1973 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - International League for the Rights of Man: "Annual Report 1973" (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - International Symposium on Communication: Technology, Impact and Policy 3/23-25/72 [Philadelphia] - Panel I (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - International Symposium - Panel II (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - International Symposium - Panel III (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - International Symposium - Panel IV (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - International Symposium - Panel V (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - International Symposium - Panel VI (part 1) (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - International Symposium - Panel VI (part 2) (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - ILS (Individual Learning Systems, Inc.) - introductox Sociology, vol. 1, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Kenneth Johnson, Hiltz, Turoff, "The success of Group Decision Making in Face to Face vs. Computerized Conferences" (Box 19, Folder 35)
    [Robert Stern letter to RKG 2/81]
  - Nicholas Johnson (Box 19, Folder 36)
    ["Freedom to Create: The Implicatior of Antitrust Policy for Television Programming Center 12/69; "What Do We Do About Television?" 7/70; letter to RKG 4-6/77]
  - K [Edward L. Kain & Tom Luster, "Advertising and Sex Roles in the US: 1940-1980" 10/82; Arthur Kantrowitz, "A Technologist Looks at Ant i -Technology" 11/78; Leopold Kohr, "Small is Beautiful" 3/80; Gerd Korman letter to Alice (Box 19, Folder 37)
    [Cook?] 5/20/69; Robert E. Kraut, "Social Psychology as Science Fiction"; Irving Kristol, "A Foolish Americanism - Utopianism" 11/71; Alfred Louis Kroeber - letter from Jean -- to RKG; Herbert Krugman and Eugene Hartley, "Passive Learning from Television 1970]
  - Examples to Accompany Remarks by Michael Kagny - 5/3/85 Louis Harris Bibliography of Published Reports (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Ethan Katsch (Box 20, Folder 2)
    ["Is Television Anti-Law?.."; "TV's Reporting of China's Gang of Four Trial.." 9/82; "TV News Coverage of the US Supreme Court, 1976-1981" 12/82]
  - Natan Katzman, "Violence and Color Television" 6/71 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Eldon Kenworthy, "The Prince and the Populace: Peroi Coming to Power" 2/73 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Joseph Klapper/ "What We Know About the Effects of Mass Communication" 1966 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    [RKG corresp 9-10/72]
  - Harold W. Kohn - various articles, 1976-79 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Isaac Kramnick, "Children's Literature and Bourgeois Ideology," 5/76 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - T.S. Kuhn, The Structure of Scientific Revolutions (Box 20, Folder 8)
    ["Kennedy Question #1 - from an A exam?]
  - L (Box 20, Folder 9)
    [Christopher Lasch, The Culture of Narcissism -reviews by Walter Capps, Joe Klein; Gertrud Lenzer, review of The Dialectical Imagination bv Martin Jay; Craig Little and Richard Gelles, "'Hey You1: The Soc Psychological Implications of Forms of Address" 8/72 Salvador Luria, "A Naturalist at Large: Genesis" - F notes]
  - Jerome Lackamp and Donald Stockford, "A Time to Serve- 1973" - Cleveland Radio and TV (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Ervin Laszlo, "A Positive Approach to the Predicament of Mankind" 11/74 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Paul P. Lazarsfeld (Box 20, Folder 12)
    [lecture series; referee report c biography; article by Paul Neurath]
  - Eric H. Lenneberg, "Language, Evolution and Purposive Behavior" 1960 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Gerhard Lenski - Introductory Sociology syllabi (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Adeline Levine - Love Canal articles (Box 20, Folder 15)
    [Letter to RKG 10/82; Janet Rosenberg letter nominating Levine book for Mills Award 11/82]
  - Howard Liddell, "The Biology of the Prejudiced Mind" (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Seymour Martin Lipset, "Some Personal Notes for a History of the Department of Sociology at Columbia" (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - "The Civilization of Llhuros" 1972 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - LPTV Reporter 1981-82 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Jack Lyle and Heidi Hoffman, "Children's use of Television and other Media" 2/71 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - M (Box 20, Folder 21)
    [D.M. McKay, "Ways of Looking at Perception" 1967; Gordon MacFarlane, "Business Communication in the 1980's" 9/80; Boris Mather, "The Electronic Working Environment 9/80; RKG notes on Margaret Mead, Marshall McLuhan, Lewis Mumford; Robert Morison, "Rights and Responsibilities" 4/74; Claus Mueller, "Notes on the Repression of Communicative Behavior"]
  - Valerie Ann Malhatra - three articles, vita (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Luciano Martins, "The Politics of (US) Multinational Corporations in Latin America" 12/72 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Marx and Engels - articles and RKG notes (Box 20, Folder 24)
    [26pp]
  - Armand Mattelart. Agresion desde el Espacio: cultura y napalm en la era de los satelites 1973 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Mattelart, et al, Comunicacion Masiva y Revolucion Socialista 1971 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Mattelart, La Cultura Como Empresa Multinacional 1974 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    [+ RKG notes on Mattelart and Ariel Dorfman. Para Leer Pato Donald]
  - Mattelart, "El Imperialismo en Busca de la Contrarrevolucion Cultural" 7/73 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Mattelart, "La Industria Cultural no es una Industria Ligera hacia la Fase Superior del Monopolismo Cultural" 3-4/73 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Emile McAnany, "Radio's Role in Development" 9/73 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Jean McNulty, "Other Voices in Broadcasting: The Evolution of New Forms of Local Programming in Canada 1979, pp. 1-152 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - McNulty, 1979, p. 153 - end (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - William H. Melody, "Children's Television: Economics j Public Policy" 12/72 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Douglas Meservey, "Fourier Analysis and Biofeedback Control of Brainwave Spectra" 2/73 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Messenger Lectures, 1978-80 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Joshua Meyrowitz (Box 20, Folder 36)
    ["The Rise of "Middle Region' politics" 6/77; "From Private to Public: the Electronic Transformation of the Spoken Word" 1981; "Television and the Obliteration of Childhood" 4/81]
  - Ellen Mickiewicz, "Media and the Russian Public," pp 109 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Mickiewicz, "Media and the Russian Public," p 110 - end (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Kieth W. Mielke, "Research and Evaluation in Educational TV" 3/73 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Ronald Milawsky and Burton Pekowsky, "Exposure to TV Violence" and Aggressive Behavior in Boys, Examined Process: A Progress Report" 3/73 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Stanley Milgram, "Conscience and Congress: The Dilemmas of Obedience" 12/73 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Stanley Milgram and Lance Shetland, "Television and Anti-Social Behavior Field Experiments" 1972 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - C. Wright Mills, The Sociological Imagination 1959 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Sidney Mintz, "Choice and Occasion: sweet Moments" 3/80 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Jose A. Moreno - articles on the Dominican Republic, vita (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Jose A. Moreno - articles on Cuba (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Thomas Mulholland, "A Program for the EEG Study of Attention in Visual Communication" 10/76 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    [RKG letter]
  - Lewis Mumford (Box 21, Folder 3)
    ["Authoritarian Technics 5/76; "Prologue to Our Time" 3/75; RKG notes 4pp, etc]
  - Nacirema (Neil B. Thompson article); related notes and clippings (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - NAEB [National Association of Educational Broadcaster - "The Hidden Medium: Educational Radio, A status Report" 11/68 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the USA "The Plutonium Economy" (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Dorothy Nelkin, "East Boston is not an Airport" 3/73, chs. 1-5 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Nelkin, "East Boston..." chs. 6-8 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Network Project Notebooks (Box 21, Folder 9)
    [Greg Knox letter 10/73]
  - New York University Media Ecology Program (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - "Not Pit to Print: The Individual vs. the Media" (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Thomas O'Brien, "The Federal communications Commissi (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Jerrold Oppenheim, "Soapbox Television" 6/71 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Sandra Ospina, "Folclor Manufacturado" 8/72 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - P (Box 21, Folder 15)
    [Edward Palmer, "Formative Research in the Product of Television for Children" 3/72; L.G. Parratt -letters, notes 1974; Joseph John Pergola, "Summary of thesis on TV families" 7/74; Henry Phillips, "Learning from our Mistakes" 3/79: Kevin Phillips. The Media: Power and the Glory - review; Jean Piaqet - articles David Elkind, Howard Gardner; Neil Postman, "Propaganda"; William Provine, "Geneticists and the Biology of Race Crossing"]
  - Richard Patch - American University Field staff arti 1964-66 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Alan Pearce, "The Economics of Network Children's Television Programming" (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Michael Pollak, "La rationalisation de la sexualite" 1977 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Michael Pollak, "Paul Lazarsfeld: A Socio-Intellectua Biography" (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Stephen M. Pollock, "Social Systems: Closing the Loop 1973 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Fred Powledge, "An ACLU Guide to Cable Television" IS (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Primetime Proposal - TVTV, San Francisco, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - R [James Randi, "Semiotics: A View From Behind the Footlights"; Richard Reeves, "The Dangers of TV in the Silverman Era" 4/78; Whitman Richards, "The Fortification Illusions of Migraines" 5/71 w/ RKG notes Ip; Philip Rieff, Fellow Teachers 1973 - chapter, qui Arthur Ruoff, "Teaching with a Packaged Course: Introductory Materials Science" w/ RKG corresp; Bertrand Russell. The ABC of Relativity 19691 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Radical Software: The TV Environment, Raindance Foundation, Ruby, NY 1973 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Sergio Ramirez Lamus, "Razon Dominante y Realismo Magico," Sociedad Antropologica de Colombia, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Marcus Raskin, "Notes Toward Reconstruction" Amherst Conference, 10/79 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - O. Lee Reed, "Mind Management: Advertisers and Your Brain" (Box 21, Folder 27)
    [w/ OLR letter to RKG 9/80]
  - Charles Reich, "The New Property" 1968 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Herbert G. Reid, "American Social Science in the Politics of Time" 1973 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Helen Roberts, "The Development of an integrated Bilingual and Cross-cultural Curriculum in an Arctic School District" 6/78 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Robertson, "Sociology: A New Look at a Familiar World (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Edmund Rogoff, "Television in Latin America" 1980 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Roper Research Associates - 3 reports (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - D.L. Rosenhan, "On Being Sane in Insane Places" 1973 some other examples) (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - James W. Rowe, American University Field staff report: 1964 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Roper Public opinion Research Center: Survey Data for Trend Analysis: An Index to Repeated Questions in US National Surveys 1975 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - RTE (Radio Telefis Eirann) Handbook 1977 and Annual Report 1976, Dublin (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - S (Box 21, Folder 38)
    [Pierre Schneider, "Paris: Dangers of Museum Bigness 5/74; E.F. Schumacher - talk at Cornell 10/75 (RKG notes llpp); Frances Wilson Schwartz - study of creative processes of males and females; Richard Sennet -articles, letter to RKG; Shockley-Montagu debate 12/73 RKG comments Ip; Kalman and Frieda Silvert, "Faith, Chance and Faith" - Cuba 9/74; Peter Singer, "Discovering Karl Popper," 5/74; Harry Skornia, "Brie Report of Sabbatical Project" 3/72; Philip Slater, The Pursuit of Loneliness - RKG notes 2pp; M. Brewster Smith, "A Psychologist's Perspective on Public Opinion Theory" 1971; Red Smith - sports articles; George Steiner, "The Baroque Novel" 1960; Tom Sullenberger, "Folklure" 6/75]
  - Morley Safer/ "Morley Safer 's Vietnam: A Personal Report" CBS News 4/67 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Seymour Sarason - 2 articles, RKG correspondence (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Thomas C. Schelling, "On the Ecology of Micromotives" 1971 (Box 21, Folder 41)
    [w/ John Platt, "Social Traps" 8/73]
  - Herbert Schiller (Box 21, Folder 42)
    ["The Polling Industry.." 12/71; "Madison Avenue Imperialism" 1972; "Chile: An End to Cultural Colonialism" 3/72; "Authentic National Development versus the Free Flow of Information and the New Communications Technology" c. 1972; "Les mecanismes de la domination internationale" 12/74; "Transnational Business, the Free Flow of Information, and the Ques of Regulation" 1979; RKG notes]
  - Tony Schwartz. The Responsive Chord 1974 (Box 21, Folder 43)
    [excerpt, RKG notes]
  - Robert Louis Shayon - speeches, RKG correspondence (Box 21, Folder 44)
    [Panel on "TV and Politics" 10/70; Cable TV Seminar 9/71; "Education, Media, and Identity" 1971; Symposium on "TV Violence and Social Policy" 4/72; "The Development of Access in Broadcasting - An Overview" 10/72; "The Second Act" 10/72]
  - Robert Louis Shayon, "What Shall We Do With Thursday Child?" pp. 1-105 (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - Shayon, "What Shall We Do..." pp. 106-end (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - B.F. Skinner (Box 21, Folder 47)
    ["Why Don't We Use the Behavioral Sciences?" 1978; Christopher Lehmann-Haupt, "Beyond B. F. Skinner?" - review of Visceral Learning by Gerald Jonas Ron Horst, "An Analysis of Operant Conditioning for theNew World" 1974]
  - David B. Smith and Roger M. Battistella, "Towards a Definition of Health Services Management: A Humanist Orientation" 1973 (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - Dallas W. Smythe, "Mass Communications and Cultural Revolution: The Experience of China." International Symposium on Communication 3/23-5/72 (Box 21, Folder 49)
  - Alexander Solzhenitsyn (Box 22, Folder 1)
    ["A World Split Apart" 8/78; "The Exhausted West" 7-8/78; newspaper clippings 1974; Marcus Raskin, "Soviet Dissent: In Search of Forgotten Men" 1974; George Steiner, "The Forests of the Night" 1974]
  - The Space Factory (Denise Warren/Marie Forester) (Box 22, Folder 2)
    [corresp 6-12/79]
  - Ralph Stavins, Television Today: The End of Communication and the Death of Community - Fart I (Washington/ DC: Institute for Policy Studies, 1969) (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Ralph Stavins, Television Today - Part I (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Ralph Stavins, Television Today - Part III (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Ralph Stavins, Television Today - Part IV: Appendix (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Aletha Huston Stein/ et al: "TV content and Young Children's Behavior11 - final report to the National Institute of Mental Health, pp. 1-68 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Stein/ et al/ pp. 69-end (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - William stein/ "Countrymen and Townsmen in the Callejon de Huaylas/ Peru/" Council on International Studies/ SUNY-Buffalo/ 1974 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Surgeon General's scientific Advisory committee on Television and Social Behavior, "TV and Growing Up: The Impact of Televised Violence" 12/71 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    [John P. Murray, "Television and Violence: Implications of the Surgeon General's Research Program"]
  - John W. Sutherland ["Beyond Behaviorism and Determinism" (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Albert Szymanski, "Marxism and Science," The Insurgent Sociologist Spring 1973 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Albert Szymanski. Marx's Sociology - "Introduction" (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - T (Box 22, Folder 14)
    [Jim Thomas, "The Ideological Control of Knowledge Production: Federal Sponsorship and Social Research" 6/80; William Irwin Thompson, At the Edge of History RKG notes]
  - J. Walter Thompson, Miscomprehension, PP. 1-62 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Thompson, Miscomprehension, PP. 63-end (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - E.A. Tinberqren and N. Tinbergen, Early Childhood Autism 1972 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Gaye Tuchman (Box 22, Folder 18)
    ["Mass Media Values" 1976; RKG notes on anthology]
  - Colin Turnbull |"The Mountain People review by Robert Coles 3/73, RKG notes; correspondence, RKG notes re Turnbull 's visit to Cornell 10/25/73, Gabriela Samper's death 1974] (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - "UHF Television" (Box 22, Folder 20)
    [anon, typescript, n.d.]
  - U.S. Navy Electronics Laboratory, NEL Deep Submerge Log No. 3 2/67 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - V-W (Box 22, Folder 22)
    [Eric Veblen, "Newspaper Impact in Election Campaigns: The Case of Two New England States" 1969 dissertation - title page; Eliseo Veron, Comunicacion de masas y produccion de ideologia.." 1974; Donald P. Warwick, "Tearoom Trade: means and ends in social research"; Arthur I. Waskow, letter to Herbert J. Bernstein re "reconstructive knowledge"; Alan Watts, The Book: On the Taboo Against Knowing Who You Are - RKi notes; Joseph Weizenbaum, "Technological Detoxification"; Edward 0. Wilson, Sociobioloqy - review by C.H. Waddington 8/75]
  - John Francis Walsh, "Dramaturgy and Mystification: Political Life in the United states" 6/80 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Scott Ward, Effects of TV Advertising on Children and Adolescents 1971, Sections 1-2 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Ward, Effects of TV Advertising.., Sections 3-4 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Ward, Effects of TV Advertising.., Sections 5-7 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Barbel Wallisch-Prinz, A Sociology of Freedom: George Simmel's Social Theory typescript 1975 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - WBAI: "Feedback" #1,2 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    ["Introduction to TV as a Medium" "The Image Empire"]
  - WBAI: "Feedback" #4,5 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    ["A Cultural Critique of Broadcast Journalism"; "A Cultural Critique of Broadcast Entertainment"]
  - Allen Wells, "Mass Media Systems, Economic Development, and the Public-Private Continuum" 1972 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Andrew Well, The Natural Mind: Beyond Drugs - A New Way of Looking At Hiaher Consciousness 1972 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - William Foote Whyte ["Mapping the Territory Theoretically: Rough Sketch for a Theoretical Framework"; "1981 ASA Meeting to Explore Frontiers of Social Inventions" (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Ken Wilbur, "Eye to Eye"; "Spectrum Psychology" 1978- (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Robin M. Williams, Jr. (Box 22, Folder 34)
    ["The Urbane Society: Emerging Forms of Organization and Change" 1967; "Sociology and the Survey Method: The Impact on Theory" 1970; "Resolving and Restricting International Conflicts" 1979; "Resolving and Restricting International Conflicts in the 1980s" 1979]
  - Langdon Winner, "Do Artifacts Have Politics?" 1979; "Technologies as Forms of Life" 1978; RKG notes (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Robert Paul Wolff, Barrington Moore, Jr. and Herbert Marcuse, A Critique of Pure Tolerance 1965 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - "Women and Media 2." The Tribune #23 (1983) (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Women in the Wasteland Fight Back - A Report on the Image of Women Portrayed in TV Programming 1972 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - T.R. Young (Box 22, Folder 39)
    ["The Annotated Oz: A Radical Exegesis"; "Research in the Land of Oz: .. .American Sociology"; " Dramaturgical Society" 9/78; "A Theory of Underground Structures.." 7/79; "The Structure of Self in Mass Society: Against Zurcher" 4/80; "The Sociology of Human Rights" 8/80; "Cultural Marxism: An Introduction" 12/80 "The Typification of Christ at Christmas and Easter.. 11/81; "Information, Ideology and Political Reality" 4/82; "Mass Medicine in America: The Swine Flu Vaccine 8/82; "The Radical Impulse in Sociological Theory"; " Structure of Democratic Communications"]
  - Philip C. Zimbardo - simulated prison research (Box 22, Folder 40)
    [Craig Haney, Curtis Banks and Zimbardo, "Interpersonal Dynamics in a Simulated Prison"; "A Pirandellian prison" 4/73 w/ exchange of letters to editor; "The Social Disease Called Shyness" 5/75]
  - Herbert Zimiles, "A Radical and Regressive Solution to the Problem of Evaluation" 6/73 (Box 22, Folder 41)
    [w/ RKG letter to H.Z.]
- Series VI Subject Files
  - Surveys and Commercials
    - Opinion Research - Caravan Surveys (Henry Dursin -Princeton) 2 Questions - 3/72 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Caravan Survey 10/72 - 1/73 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Sample Survey; "Public Interest" correspondence; Opinion Research, Gallup/Conway - June 1979 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Lou Harris telephone survey (Bob Moss) - 6-7/79 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Sample Survey: United Church of Christ (Jan Engsberg); National Organization for Women - D.C. (Kathy Bonk) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Proposal for Survey: Ford/Markle/United Church of Christ 6-10/79 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Commercials - Daily Log (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Index to Commercials on Cassettes (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Index to Commercials (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Funding Sources
    - Research proposals - ideas 1974 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Proposal for circulation 10/8/80 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Grants 1980-81 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Foundations A-P (miscellaneous) (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - American Academy of Advertising (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Aspen Institute (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Benton Foundation (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Carnegie Corporation (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Federal grant information - miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Federal Communications Commission (FCC) (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Federal Trade Commission (FTC) (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Foundation for Character Education (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Foundation for Child Development (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Fulbright - CIES - Colombia, etc. (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Fulbright - CIES - Spain 4/81 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Fulbright Committee - Cornell (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Fulbright -Hays (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Funding sources - unclassified (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - General Education Board (Cornell) - Goldsen/Waugh cours proposal 1981 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - German Marshall Fund (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Guggenheim Foundations (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Hastings Institute (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Hogg Foundation (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Institute for Development of Educational Activities (IDEA) (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Internships - New York State Legislature (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Internships - unclassified (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Internships - undergraduate summer (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Kellogg Foundation (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Charles Stewart Mott Foundation (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - NCCB Summer Intern Program, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - National Institutes of Health (NIH); National Instituti of Mental Health (NIMH) (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF) (Box 9, Folder 56)